<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on I am Georgios</title>
    <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on I am Georgios</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:21:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gkalogiros.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>life in the Terminal Volume 1 - LSOF</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/lsof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 11:29:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/lsof/</guid>
      <description>Life in the Terminal - Volume 1 The terminal is the best friend of an application developer. There are multiple tools that can be piped together to extract meaningful insights for the problem at hand without developing a single line of code.
Today we will be exploring lsof
LSOF What is it? lsof is a command line tool that can be used for analyzing open files. The definition of file in a unix-based system is very wide: It can represent directories, text files, sockets or streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caring about security in an unsafe fast-paced world</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/caring-about-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 20:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/caring-about-security/</guid>
      <description>Caring about Security in an unsafe fast-paced world A few words about my childhood and how this connects to my deep will to care about security. Since the moment I started fiddling around with computers, I realised how important it is, keeping my private data, for personal consumption only. For every digital movement I used to do, installing a program or simply creating a file with the wrong permissions, It was clear that a risk was arising.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to become a meeting guru?</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 22:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/meetings/</guid>
      <description>Meetings constitute a very effective way for a team to discuss problems and take decisions.
Unfortunately, many teams, including mine, abuse the ability to organize meetings and end up failing the primary goal of such a ceremony which is taking a decision.
I was really curious about whether there are other teams out there having similar productivity issues. I kicked off an extensive reasearch (I was actually eating popcorns and reading several posts on Reddit) and tried to extract some intel that would later help my team become more effective when conducting meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum process</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/dev-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 02:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/dev-process/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of the Agile development process. I am also a big fan of Scrum. This is the typical set of ceremonies that we use to organize:
Standup    When Duration Location     Every day 10&amp;rsquo; Zoom Channel or Team area    This is the typical 10 minute meeting where we share our updates. The standup has been scheduled early in the morning so that we can kick-start the day with having a plan in mind or focus on solving any blockers awaiting from the previous day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning your startup project</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/startup-bootsrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 11:05:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/startup-bootsrap/</guid>
      <description>This article will be devoted to a major task that should be considered before designing the next $$$$-billion start-up. It&amp;rsquo;s all about planning technologies, processes, the future, monetization, databases everything. When you develop technology products, many things can go wrong and you should be ahead by following a strict plan.
Below I cite the plan that I usually follow when building the ideas I have (unsuccessfully most of the times but I believe this is a good plan though!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vi cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/vi/</guid>
      <description>Navigation left/up/down/right
hjkl  move to the start of the file
gg  move to the end of file
Shift+g  move to the start of the next word
w  move to the end of the next word
Shift+e  move to the end of the line
Shift+$  move to the start of the line
0  Actions Switch to visual mode
Esc  Text Edit Start Editing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unix</title>
      <link>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 11:45:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gkalogiros.com/posts/unix/</guid>
      <description>File Search *find . -name &amp;ldquo;dev&amp;ldquo;: Find files containing dev in current and sub directories</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>